### **Ihor Hontarenko**

**UI** Engineer

+380 66 102 10 41 igor.gontarenko@gmail.com Kyiv, Ukraine

# Summary

I'm specializing in web development with 6+ years of professional experience with a full understanding of the web development process, including design, development, and deployment. I have high-level operability, can work independently, and use resources efficiently.



## Experience

Company «Perfectial», Kyiv, Ukraine UI Engineer Feb 2020 - Present

- styling React elements with JSX on TypeScript by using SCSS
- creating animations by using CSS3, Scalable Vector Graphics, GreenSock Animation Platform
- setup and development of WordPress and Shopify projects
- building a UI structure of the projects and modularize components with React
- working according to the Agile methodology by using Scrum way
- estimations of the implementation of part of the UI for projects
- reviewing teammates' pull requests on the Bitbucket
- support existing projects

Company «Clock Creative Lab», Kyiv, Ukraine Front-End Web Developer

Mar 2017 - Jan 2020

- markup HTML5 layouts from scratch on SCSS by using BEM methodology
- creating animations by using JavaScript, jQuery, CSS3, Scalable Vector Graphics
- code verification and merging pull requests on the GitHub
- distribution of technical tasks between developers
- building Progressive Web Apps

Company «Mediaset», Kyiv, Ukraine Full Stack Web Developer Nov 2015 - Mar 2017

- markup HTML layouts from scratch on Less
- creating animations by using JavaScript, jQuery
- setup and development of WordPress and Django projects
- find and use new web technologies to solve problems

#### Education

National Technical University of Ukraine «Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute»

2015 - 2017

Faculty of Informatics and Computer Technology

Master's degree

Computer Science

National Technical University of Ukraine «Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute»

2011 - 2015

Faculty of Informatics and Computer Technology

Bachelor's degree

Computer Science

#### Skills

- proficient in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, Scalable Vector Graphics, GreenSock Animation Platform, Three.js, Progressive Web App
- good knowledge of TypeScript, React, Redux, JSX, REST, Asynchronous JavaScript and XML
- working with Bootstrap, Materialize, and some other frameworks
- using Gulp, Webpack toolkits, and BEM methodology to enhance workflow
- working knowledge of MySQL and some CMS such as WordPress and Shopify
- using version control systems and development team workflow such as Agile, Scrum, Kanban
- proficient understanding of concept development, layout composition, site functionality, navigation, and understanding of building responsive, valid, cross-browser friendly applications
- great experience in implementing UI design, ability to translate it from design platforms into clean, accurate code by using pixel perfect, sprites, code linting
- effectively wield of refactoring and design patterns

### Additional Information

- developed the official websites Eurovision Song Contest Kyiv, Mercedes-Benz Ukraine, Audi Ukraine, and KIA Motors Ukraine Progressive Web App for Car Service & Repair
- obtained 3D Programming with JavaScript and Three.js 3D Library certificate
- obtained certificates of achievement: HTML, CSS and JavaScript Essential
- obtained Luxoft Agile Practice certificate on the Scrum Basics Workshop
- took part in the UA Web Challenge

English - B2 Languages

gontarenko.pp.ua t.me/mysecondspace References

> linkedin.com/in/gontarenko github.com/mysecondspace